# Summary\_

I am a research scholar at Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA, United States. I worked for Tesla, Palo Alto, CA, United States, as a Senior Machine Learning Scientist. I received my M.S and Ph.D. degrees in Electrical Engineering from KAIST, Korea in 2014 and 2019 respectively. During my graduate study, I worked at the Robotics and Computer Vision Lab under the supervision of Prof. In So Kweon. In 2016, I worked for Qualcomm Research, Vienna, Austria, as a Research Intern. I received Samsung HumanTech Paper Awards (Gold prize in 2017, honorable mention in 2018) and the 1st place at NVidia Korea Deep learning Contest in 2016. I received my B.S degree in Electronics and Computer Engineering from Hanyang University, Korea in 2012. My research area includes computer vision, deep learning, and sensor fusion.

### **Education**

#### KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, S.Korea

Mar. 2014 - Feb. 2019

PH.D. • Dissertation: Learning based Adaptive Visual Sensor Fusion for Robust Pedestrian Detection

• Advisor: Prof. In So Kweon

#### KAIST (Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology)

Daejeon, S.Korea Feb. 2012 - Feb. 2014

• Thesis: A Hierarchical Classifier Model based on Deformable Part Models and Random Forest for Robust Pedestrian Detection

· Advisor: Prof. In So Kweon

**Hanyang University** Seoul, S.Korea

Mar. 2007 - Feb. 2012

• Recognize and Play Sheet Music on Android Smartphone

# Research Interests

#### Computer vision for self-driving cars

- Object detection (e.g. pedestrians, cars)
- Learning based depth estimation / Semantic segmentation
- Image enhancement / 3D scene understanding

#### **Sensor fusion**

- RGB camera + Thermal camera (Long wavelength IR)
- RGB camera + 3D LiDAR
- · Adaptive fusion

# **Experience**

Research Scholar Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, US

CARNEGIE MELLON UNIVERSITY, THE ROBOTICS INSTITUTE Sep. 2021 - Current

### Sr. Machine Learning Scientist

AUTOPILOT TEAM, TESLA

• Train/Develop neural networks for autopilot

#### **Full-time Research Intern**

COMPUTER VISION GROUP, QUALCOMM RESEARCH

· Lane detection using deep neural network

#### **Full-time Intern**

MIXED REALITY LAB. (PROF. JONG-IL PARK)

• Development of view morphing system for relics

Palo Alto, California, US

May. 2019 - Feb. 2021

Vienna, Austria

Jul. 2016 - Nov. 2016

Hanyang Univ., Seoul, S.Korea

Nov. 2010 - Feb. 2011

**Projects** 

#### **Automatic Emergency Braking for Pedestrian Protection**

MINISTRY OF TRADE, INDUSTRY AND ENERGY OF KOREA (MOTIE)

Jun. 2013 - Jun. 2018

• Accurate pedestrian detection using multiple sensor fusion

#### Personal Plug and Play DigiCar (P3 DigiCar)

NATIONAL RESEARCH FOUNDATION OF KOREA

Mar. 2012 - Feb. 2017

· Robust pedestrian detection using monocular camera

#### DATMO: Detection and Tracking Moving Object using 3D LiDAR

LIG-Nex1 Co. Ltd, S.Korea

Apr. 2015 - Nov. 2015

- On-road object detection and tracking (pedestrian, car) using 3D-LiDAR
- Camera & 3D LiDAR fusion

#### Monocular Vision based Natural Feature Extraction for Cognitive Model

MINISTRY OF KNOWLEDGE ECONOMY OF KOREA

Sep. 2012 - Dec. 2013

• Porting developed natural feature algorithm to embedded system

# **Publications**

\* indicates equal contribution.

#### **Gated Bidirectional Feature Pyramid Network for Accurate One Shot Detection**

MACHINE VISION AND APPLICATIONS (MVA)

2019

Sanghyun Woo, **Soonmin Hwang**, Ho-Deok Jang, In So Kweon

#### **KAIST Multispectral Recognition Dataset in Day and Night**

IEEE Transactions on Intelligent Transportation Systems (TITS)

2018

Yukyung Choi, Namil Kim, **Soonmin Hwang**, Kibaek Park, Jae Shin Yoon, Kyunghwan An, In So Kweon

#### StairNet: Top-Down Semantic Aggregation for Accurate One Shot Detection

Lake Tahoe, USA

Mar 2018

IEEE WINTER CONF. ON APPLICATIONS OF COMPUTER VISION (WACV)

Sanghyun Woo, **Soonmin Hwang**, In So Kweon

The 24th HumanTech Paper Award, Samsung Electronics, Hornorable Mention (\$2,000)

Multispectral Transfer Network: Unsupervised Depth Estimation for All-day Vision

THE THIRTY-SECOND AAAI CONFERENCE ON ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE (AAAI)

Namil Kim\*, Yukyung Choi\*, **Soonmin Hwang**, In So Kweon

The 23th HumanTech Paper Award, Samsung Electronics, Gold Prize (\$10,000)

KAIST R&D Report, Research Highlights of 2017

#### New Orleans, USA Feb. 2018

# Thermal Image Enhancement using Convolutional Neural Network

THE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE OF INTELLIGENT ROBOTS AND SYSTEMS (IROS)

Namil Kim\*, Yukyung Choi\*, **Soonmin Hwang\***, In So Kweon

Deep Learning Contest, NVidia Korea, 1st Place

KAIST R&D Report, Research Highlights of 2017

#### Daejeon, S.Korea

Oct. 2016

# Fast Multiple Objects Detection and Tracking Fusing Color Camera and 3D LIDAR for Intelligent Vehicles

Xian, China

International Conference on Ubiquitous Robots and Ambient Intelligence (URAI)

Soonmin Hwang\*, Namil Kim\*, Yukyung Choi, Seokju Lee, In So Kweon

Aug. 2016

#### Thermal-Infrared based Drivable Region Detection

IEEE INTELLIGENT VEHICLES SYMPOSIUM (IV)

Gothenburg, Sweden

Jun. 2016

Jae Shin Yoon, Kibaek Park, **Soonmin Hwang**, Namil Kim, Yukyung Choi, In So Kweon

#### **Low-Cost Synchronization for Multispectral Cameras**

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON UBIQUITOUS ROBOTS AND AMBIENT INTELLIGENCE (URAI)

Soonmin Hwang, Yukyung Choi, Namil Kim, Kibaek Park, Jae Shin Yoon, In So Kweon

Oct. 2015

Goyang, S.Korea

#### **Geometrical Calibration of Multispectral Calibration**

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON UBIQUITOUS ROBOTS AND AMBIENT INTELLIGENCE (URAI)

Namil Kim, Yukyung Choi, **Soonmin Hwang**, Kibaek Park, Jae Shin Yoon, In So Kweon

Goyang, S.Korea
Oct. 2015

#### **ARTRIEVAL: Painting Retrieval Without Expert Knowledge**

IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON IMAGE PROCESSING (ICIP)

Namil Kim, Yukyung Choi, Soonmin Hwang, In So Kweon

Québec, Canada

#### All-Day Visual Place Recognition: Benchmark Dataset and Baselines

IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER VISION AND PATTERN RECOGNITION WORKSHOPS (CVPRW-VPRICE)

Yukyung Choi, Namil Kim, Kibaek Park, **Soonmin Hwang**, Jae Shin Yoon, In So Kweon

Boston, USA

Sep. 2015

Jun. 2015

#### Multispectral Pedestrian Detection: Benchmark Dataset and Baselines

IEEE INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER VISION AND PATTERN RECOGNITION (CVPR)

Soonmin Hwang, Jaesik Park, Namil Kim, Yukyung Choi, In So Kweon

Current citation: 399

Boston, USA

Jun. 2015

#### A Two Phase Approach for Pedestrian Detection

ASIAN CONFERENCE ON COMPUTER VISION WORKSHOPS (ACCV WORKSHOPS)

Soonmin Hwang, Tae-hyun Oh, In So Kweon

Singapore, Singapore

Nov. 2014

#### **Evaluation of Vocabulary Trees for Localization in Robot Applications**

INTERNATIONAL CONFERENCE ON CONTROL, AUTOMATION AND SYSTEMS (ICCAS)

**Soonmin Hwang**, Chaehoon Park, Yukyung Choi, Donggeun Yoo, In So Kweon

Gwangju, S.Korea

Oct. 2013

#### Patents\_

# Apparatus and Method for Depth Estimation Based on Thermal Image, and Neural Network Learning Method

KR 10-1947782 (2019.02.07) Registered

**Apparatus and Method for Thermal Image Enhancement** 

KR 10-1821285 (2018.01.17) Registered

**Method and Apparatus for Detecting Smoke from Image** 

KR 10-1932543 (2015.02.03), US 20150030203 (2015.01.29), CN 104346618 (2015.02.11) Registered

Pattern Board for Geometrical Calibration in Multi-Spectral Camera System, Calibration

**Apparatus, and Calibration Method Thereof** 

KR 10-2016-0122950 (2016.09.26)

Pending

# Honors & Awards

2018	KAIST R&D Report	Research Highlights of 2017 (IROS'16, AAAI'18)
2018	Travel grant	Research Supporting Program for CVPR 2018, Kakao Corp.(\$4,300)
2018	<b>Honorable mention</b>	The 24th HumanTech Paper Award, Samsung Electronics Co. Ltd, (\$2,000, acceptance rate 6.5%)
2017	Gold prize	The 23th HumanTech Paper Award, Samsung Electronics Co. Ltd, (\$10,000, acceptance rate 0.7%)
2016	1st Place	NVidia Deep Learning Contest, NVidia Korea
2016	Bronze prize	Korea Invention Patent Exhibition (KINPEX)

# Reviewers

**IEEE Winter Conference on Applications of Computer Vision (WACV)** 

**IEEE Transaction on Intelligent Transportation Systems (TITS)** 

**IEEE Transactions on Aerospace and Electronic Systems (TAES)** 

**IEEE Transactions on Cybernetics** 

**Springer The Visual Computer (TCVJ)** 

# Skills\_\_\_\_\_

**Languages** Python, MATLAB, C/C++

**Libraries** PyTorch, Caffe, OpenCV, QT, PCL, MFC, and others